all right I want to make a quick video
about chat about WeChat so some of you
know that I've been doing videos lately
and I've gone back to using chat on the
screen go back and look at my live
videos so something that's new that I've
been doing that is also an old thing
I've been doing is I've gone back to
having chat on the screen using IRC and
this video is about IRC Internet relay
chat why you should still learn it why
you should use it in 2024 and how you
can use it to participate from YouTube
in particular on my live streams that my
Marathon live stream coding session so I
regularly just to give you some context
I have regularly go back and look at my
live I I've been regularly streaming
yesterday I did a 12 hour stream from
twitch where I just coded the whole
entire time I was coding I was talking I
was taking breaks coffee breaks I was
walking the dog I was doing all kinds of
things and and the community was in here
having fun in IRC and the IRC was on the
screen it appears at the bottom of the
screen and I'm not going to do that
right now because I don't want to ruin
the video with somebody saying something
that you know gets published there but
the reason I do it is because I'm able
to watch the screen and I can see all
the chat as it's happening while I'm
writing code or doing whatever and I
don't have to multitask and go back and
forth with OBS uh and for that reason I
turn off the live chat from YouTube I
stream to YouTube even though they they
cut me off after six hours I still
stream to YouTube but but the YouTube
stuff the chat is turned off why because
when it's not turned off inevitably
people will be saying things out there
that I can't see they feel like they're
being you know not attended to and or
else they worse they start saying
horrible things that I don't see it
because it's not in front of me so when
I'm doing these like just stream from my
computer usually I'm not showing my face
sometimes if I am it's Bubblehead Rob um
and you know so the the point of it is
that you you can't participate in the
chat and in our community and I won't
see what you have to say unless you use
twitch but there's a catch twitch uses
IRC under the hood it's one of the most
intelligent design decisions twitch ever
made twitch decided that hey let's not
rebuild a chat system let's use an
existing one and so they have sort of a
boiled down you know watered down
version of IRC that they use for twitch
what does that mean that means that you
can think use things like what I have on
the screen here you can use wehat WeChat
from the terminal and you can actually
participate in chat and just fire it up
in fact I'm going to go ahead and at the
risk of being in trouble IRS irssi is
horrible don't use that use WeChat if
you're going to use a terminal base chat
trust me on this one trust me unless you
want to really really suffer don't use
anything but we chat on the RC that's my
recommendation if you if you want to try
to you know push the old school IR SSI
that we used to use back in the 90s and
say okay Boomer you use irssi we're all
going to use WeChat which is way better
if you want to know it's actually the
spiritual ancestor of bitchx that's the
official name uh that is really popular
with hackers and others so if you're
going to use ter teral chat use we chat
that's the takeaway if you're not though
what chat should you use um the chat
that you should probably use is hex chat
and I'm going to go do a search really
quick for hex chat let's see if we can
get one here let's do uh hex chat let's
do a search for hex chat and hex chat
let's
see is a discontinued Internet relay
chat client is used and is a for how
come it's
discontinued is hexat really
discontinued they I didn't hear that
they did that so you just that's I just
reading that right
now so this is hex chat look at that man
discontinu really chat a lot of and is a
for X chat it has the choice to same so
so so so should we be using X I don't
know I use the
terminal yeah so I don't know what do
you think let's let's ask Chloe what she
thinks uh what are the
best IRC clients
uh today it's going to say WeChat and
irssi and it's going to say I mean
really if you're using IRC you should be
using a terminal in my opinion but you
know if you're on Windows you don't have
that option so WeChat is still the
leader xhat is still listed pretty high
kiwi's up
there
MRC uh what is what is MRC the
lounge what is this
one I don't know what that is but that's
is that a link or an
executable yeah anyway so those are the
the chat clients so um what I will
return to is telling you how to set it
up so so it help me search videos three
to four months time uh this is a video
so yes I'm recording it so this this
will get a video this otherwise I'm
posting to live yeah I'm not adding
titles to my regular live streams I'm
not adding titles ever the only thing
that'll have a title is something that's
actually about the thing that's in the
title from now on so just so you know
every time I make T I made a whole video
about it so anyway if you're going back
to hex chat let's let's go back to hex
chat here and um so this is how you do
it okay the bottom line the main thing
you need to know I mean you're smart
people you can figure this out go in
there and configure it this is in the
dot template so if you guys know what
the do template is this is in this is in
github.com RBX rob. template under weed
there's a setup script in here you can
use the setup script if you want you
have bash um this works with uh this
this works with with bash for Windows
but the problem is is that Windows
doesn't come with WeChat there's no way
to get it you can't install it using
wiget uh same with t-mo same with w3m
and links links can't do that um so uh
still use I don't know if we chat hex
chat I used to use hex chat today I just
learned that you can't use hex chat
because it's the thing but the main
takeaway here is see this website right
here and I'm not going to click on it
but if you go to that oath website
that's the same one I use for my IRC
streaming I know that it's valid there
are a couple of sites that um are
considered authoritative when it comes
to giving you a token but what you do is
you go there you click on a thing and
you copy and paste that token and then
when it prompts you for your token uh it
will put it into the into the into the
code where it belongs and let me show
you where it belongs if you want to send
any of these commands if these are all
the commands that I have that set up the
different colors and stuff for we chat
but you can go in here and um you you
obviously have to set your your user um
if you set your own user that will log
into to you but if you want to set you
can have your username be this and then
you can have Auto join the channel
obviously the channel is rwx Rob I'm
pretty sure so you can put that there
and that'll join it um and and and then
this is how you save your
password um this this will actually put
your your this puts your o token be
really careful with this um I have to be
careful not to show my my configuration
for WeChat because this is not in it's
not even OB fiscated at all it's just a
straightup token and there's no way to
disable a previous token um I mean other
than going into the developer UI
interface on Twitch I think and
disabling a token I don't think that
there's an easy way um to do that so so
just be really careful with that token
you really don't want to dox that token
um but once you have weat set up you can
come in here you can participate in the
chat uh it's up all the time it's up 247
so I have have my I'm regularly in the
chat even when I'm not streaming and you
can we can use this as kind of a a place
to do live chat I do not live chat in
Discord I don't like it um really it's
only good for other things like being
able to post uh you know videos or maybe
code or something but when it comes to
just real time you know chatting like
really simple easy chat there's nothing
better than IRC for that uh that kind of
thing and it works everywhere you can
you can put check lines on your phone
too so if you wanted to stay logged in
to the twitch uh Community you can do
that you can do this same thing by the
way if you just go to the website and
you click on me click on me and you
click on the chat button um you can you
know you can do that as well but um you
know but that that's harder and it
doesn't have history and all that stuff
when you when you do it with IRC you get
you get you get all that history around
so so it is true that the people from
YouTube who are watching this are like I
don't know how to do that that's too
much work but I'm just trying to tell
you that there is a way for you to
participate in the chat and there's
gonna be a lot of you that are going to
see this you're like that's way too much
hassle I am not doing IRC to chat with
Rob while he's in over theh shoulder
mode we call it you know or I'm just I'm
just doing something and everything's
muted uh and a lot of you are not going
to care to be here for that if that's if
it's too much of a hassle for you to sit
up by RC then just get a Twitch account
and come on in and join watch on Twitch
or or or or you know or chat from twitch
you have to have a Twitch account anyway
to use IRC so even if but if you hate
the interface if you hate the interface
and you want to use something else and
you maybe want IRC open while you're
doing something else and you just want
to have it at the bottom of your screen
like I do then you can do that you can
do that with WeChat you can set it up to
do that and you can look at my DOT files
for how to configure that that's all I'm
going to say about that